Anna. Elsa.
Bedtime soon.
Uh-oh. The princess
is trapped
in the snow goblin's
evil spell.
Quick, Elsa! Make a prince!
A fancy one!
Oh, no! The prince
is trapped, too.
Who cares about danger
when there's love?
Ugh, Anna. Bleugh!
Kissing won't save
the Forest.
The lost fairies cry out.
What sound
does a giraffe make?
Never mind.
They wake
the fairy queen...
who breaks the spell
and saves everyone!
And they all get married!
What are you playing?
Enchanted Forest.
The prince
and the princess...
Hmm. That's like no enchanted
forest I've ever seen.
You've seen
an enchanted forest?
Wait, what?
I have. Once.
And you've never
told us this before?
Well, I could
tell you now, if you...
- Okay. Now.
- Tell us now.
Are you sure about this?
It's time they know.
Let's make
a big snowman later.
If they can settle
and listen.
Far away...
as north as we can go...
stood a very old
and very enchanted forest.
But its magic wasn't that of
goblin spells
and lost fairies.
It was protected by the most
powerful spirits of all...
those of air...
of fire...
of water...
and earth.
But it was also home
to the mysterious
Northuldra people.
Were the
Northuldra magical, like me?
No, Elsa.
They were not magical.
They just took advantage
of the Forest's gifts.
Their ways
were so different from ours...
but still,
they promised us friendship.
In honor of that,
your grandfather,
King Runeard,
built them a mighty dam...
to strengthen their waters.
It was a gift of peace.
That's a big gift of peace.
And I was so honored
to get to go to the Forest
to celebrate it.
Stand tall, Agnarr.
I wasn't
at all prepared
for what the day would bring.
We let down our guard.
We were charmed.
Whoa. Whoa!
It felt so...
magical.
But something went wrong.
They were attacking us.
Get behind me.
It was
a brutal battle.
Your grandfather...
Father!
...was lost.
Aah!
The fighting
enraged the spirits.
Look out!
They turned
their magic against us all.
There was this voice...
...and someone saved me.
I'm told the spirits
then vanished.
And a powerful mist
covered the Forest.
Locking everyone out.
And that night, I came home
King of Arendelle.
Whoa, Papa, that was epic.
Whoever saved you,
I love them.
I wish I knew
who it was.
What happened to the spirits?
What's in the Forest now?
I don't know.
The mist
still stands.
No one
can get in.
And no one
has since come out.
So we're safe.
Yes.
But the Forest
could wake again.
And we must be prepared for
whatever danger it may bring.
And on that note,
how about we say good night
to your father?
But I still
have so many questions.
Save them
for another night, Anna.
You know I don't
have that kind of patience.
Why did Northuldra
attack us anyway?
Who attacks people
who give them gifts?
Do you think the
Forest will wake again?
Only Ahtohallan knows.
Octa-who-what?
When I was little...
my mother
would sing a song
about a special river
called Ahtohallan...
that was said to hold all
the answers about the past.
About what we are
a part of.
Wow.
Will you sing it
for us? Please?
Okay.
Cuddle close.
Scooch in.
♪ Where the Northwind
♪ Meets the sea
♪ There's a river
♪ Full of memory
♪ Sleep, my darling,
safe and sound
♪ For in this river,
all is found
♪ In her waters
♪ Deep and true
♪ Lie the answers
♪ And a path for you
♪ Dive down deep
into her sound
♪ But not too far
or you'll be drowned
♪ Yes, she will sing
to those who hear
♪ And in her song,
all magic flows
♪ But can you brave
what you most fear?
♪ Can you face
what the river knows?
♪ Where the Northwind
♪ Meets the sea
♪ There's a mother
♪ Full of memory
♪ Come, my darling,
homeward bound
♪ When all is lost
♪ Then all is found ♪
- Your Majesty.
- Oh!
They're ready.
Excuse me.
I'm coming.
Do you hear that?
What?
Never mind.
Enjoying
your new permafrost, Olaf?
I'm just living
the dream, Anna.
How I wish
- this could last forever.
- Mmm.
And yet, change mocks us
with her beauty.
What's that?
Forgive me.
Maturity is making me poetic.
Tell me, you're older
and thus all-knowing...
do you ever worry
about the notion that...
nothing is permanent?
Uh... No.
Really?
Wow, I can't wait until
I'm ancient like you...
so I don't have to worry
about important things.
That's not what I mean.
I don't worry because...
well, I have you and Elsa
and Kristoff and Sven...
and the gates
are open wide...
and I'm not alone anymore.
♪ Yes, the wind blows
a little bit colder
♪ And we're all getting older
♪ And the clouds are moving on
With every autumn breeze
♪ Peter Pumpkin
just became fertilizer
♪ And my leaf's
a little sadder and wiser
♪ That's why I rely
on certain certainties
♪ Yes, some things
never change
♪ Like the feel
of your hand in mine
♪ Some things
stay the same
♪ Like how we get along
just fine
♪ Like an old stone wall
that'll never fall
♪ Some things
are always true!
♪ Some things never change
♪ Like how
I'm holding on tight to you
♪ The leaves
are already falling
♪ Sven, it feels
like the future is calling
♪ Are you telling me tonight
♪ You're gonna get down
on one knee?
♪ Yeah, but I'm really bad
at planning these things out
♪ Like candlelight and
pulling of rings out
♪ Maybe you should leave
all the romantic stuff to me!
♪ Yeah, some things
never change
♪ Like the love
that I feel for her
♪ Some things stay the same
♪ Like how reindeers
are easier
♪ But if I commit
and I go for it
♪ I'll know
what to say and do!
♪ Right?
♪ Some things never change
♪ Sven, the pressure
is all on you
♪ The winds are restless
♪ Could that be why
I'm hearing this call?
♪ Is something coming?
♪ I'm not sure I want
things to change at all
♪ These days are precious
♪ Can't let them slip away
♪ I can't freeze this moment
♪ But I can still go out
and seize this day!
Oh!
♪ The wind blows
a little bit colder
♪ And you all look
a little bit older
♪ It's time to count
our blessings
♪ Beneath an autumn sky
♪ We'll always live
in a kingdom of plenty
♪ That stands
for the good of the many!
♪ And I promise you the flag
of Arendelle will always fly!
♪ Our flag will always fly!
♪ Our flag will always fly
Our flag will always fly
♪ Some things never change
♪ Turn around
and the time has flown
♪ Some things stay the same
♪ Though the future
remains unknown
♪ May our good luck last
May our past be past
♪ Time's moving fast,
it's true
♪ Some things never change
♪ And I'm holding
on tight to you
♪ Holding on tight to you
- ♪ Holding on tight to you
♪ I'm holding on tight
to you ♪
Uh, okay.
Um, lion?
Grizzly bear?
- Uh, monster?
- Brown bear?
- Angry face?
- Black bear?
- Uh...
- Hans?
Unredeemable monster?
Greatest mistake
of your life?
Wouldn't even kiss you?
Villain!
Oh!
We all kind of got it.
Okay, Olaf,
you're up.
Okay.
So much easier
now that I can read.
Mm.
Lightning round,
boys against girls.
Okay, I'm ready,
I'm ready. Go.
Unicorn.
Ice cream!
Castle! Oaken!
Teapot! Mouse!
Oh! Elsa!
I don't think Olaf
should get to rearrange.
Doesn't matter. This is gonna
be a cinch.
Two sisters, one mind.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Here we go.
You got this, Elsa.
- Hmm.
- Anytime.
Just do it with your body.
Uh, nothing?
Air? Tree? People?
Treeple? Oh,
that's not a word.
Oh, shovel boy? Teeth?
Oh! Doing the dishes?
- Polar bear?
- Hey.
- Sorry.
- Uh... Ugh.
You gotta
give me something.
Um...
Oh! Uh, alarmed?
Distracted?
Um, worried? Panicking?
Disturbed?
Oh, come on,
you definitely
look disturbed.
We won.
Rematch?
Oh, you know what?
I think I'll turn in.
Are you okay?
Just...
Just tired.
Good night.
Yeah, I'm tired, too.
And Sven promised
to read me a bedtime story.
Didn't you, Sven?
Did I?
Oh, you do
the best voices!
Like when you pretend to be
Kristoff, and you're like...
"I just
need to go talk to some rocks
"about my childhood
and stuff."
Um, how about you guys
start without me?
Ugh.
Did Elsa seem weird
to you?
- She seemed like Elsa.
- Hmm.
That last word
really seemed to throw her.
What was it?
- I don't know. Ahem.
- No. No.
- I don't know, but...
- Ah.
"Ice"?
Oh, come on!
She couldn't act out ice?
- I better go check on her.
- Uh...
- Thanks, honey. Love you.
- Hmm?
Love you, too.
It's fine.
Come in.
Yep. Something's wrong.
- With you?
- No, with you.
You're wearing
Mother's scarf.
You do that
when something's wrong.
Did we hurt
your feelings?
I'm so sorry if we did.
You know, very few people are
actually good at family games.
That's just a fact.
No, that's not it.
Then, what is it?
There's this...
I just don't wanna
mess things up.
What things?
You're doing great.
Oh, Elsa,
when are you going to see yourself
the way I see you?
What would I do without you?
You'll always have me.
I know what you need.
- Come on, come here.
- What?
In Mama's words,
- "cuddle close, scooch in."
- Mm-hmm.
♪ Where the Northwind
♪ Meets the sea
♪ There's a river
♪ Full of memory
I know what you're doing.
♪ Sleep, my darling,
safe and sound
♪ For in this river,
all is found ♪
♪ I can hear you
♪ But I won't
♪ Some look for trouble
♪ While others don't
♪ There's a thousand reasons
I should go about my day
♪ And ignore your whispers
♪ Which I wish
would go away, oh
♪ Oh
♪ You're not a voice
♪ You're just
a ringing in my ear
♪ And if I heard you
♪ Which I don't
♪ I'm spoken for, I fear
♪ Everyone I've ever loved
is here within these walls
♪ I'm sorry, Secret Siren
♪ But I'm blocking out
your calls
♪ I've had my adventure
I don't need something new
♪ I'm afraid of what I'm
risking if I follow you
♪ Into the unknown
♪ What do you want?
♪ 'Cause you've been
keeping me awake
♪ Are you here
to distract me
♪ So I make a big mistake?
♪ Or are you someone out there
♪ Who's a little bit like me
♪ Who knows deep down
♪ I'm not where
I'm meant to be?
♪ Every day's a little harder
♪ As I feel my power grow
♪ Don't you know there's
part of me that longs to go
♪ Into the unknown?
♪ Into the unknown!
♪ Whoa-oh-oh
♪ Are you out there?
Do you know me?
♪ Can you feel me?
Can you show me?
♪ Where are you going?
Don't leave me alone
♪ How do I follow you
♪ Into the unknown? ♪
Air, fire, water, earth.
The water!
The air rages,
no fire, no water.
The earth is next.
We have to get out.
It'll be okay.
Evacuate to the cliffs.
Oh, no!
I'm gonna blow!
I've got you!
Yes.
Everyone's out and safe.
- Here. Take one of these.
- Huh?
You okay there, Olaf?
Oh, yeah.
We're calling this...
"controlling what you can when
things feel out of control."
Okay, I don't understand.
You've been hearing
a voice
and you didn't think
to tell me?
I didn't want to worry you.
We made a promise not
to shut each other out.
Just tell me
what's going on.
I woke the magical spirits
at the Enchanted Forest.
Okay, that's
definitely not
what I thought
you were gonna say.
Wait. The Enchanted Forest?
The one
Father warned us about?
Yes.
Why would you do that?
Because of the voice.
I know it sounds crazy...
but I believe whoever
is calling me is good.
How can you say that?
Look at our kingdom.
I know. It's just that
my magic can feel it.
I can feel it.
Okay.
Oh, no. What now?
The Trolls?
- Kristoff! We missed you!
- Oh!
Pabbie.
Well, never a dull moment
with you two.
I hope you're prepared
for what you have done, Elsa.
Angry magical spirits are not
for the faint of heart.
Why are they still angry?
What does all of this
have to do with Arendelle?
Let me see
what I can see.
The past is not
what it seems.
A wrong demands to be righted.
Arendelle is not safe.
The truth must be found.
Without it...
I see no future.
No future?
When one can see
no future...
all one can do
is the next right thing.
The next right thing
is for me to go
to the Enchanted Forest...
and find that voice.
Kristoff, can I borrow
your wagon
- and Sven?
- Hmm?
I'm not very comfortable
with the idea of that.
- You are not going alone.
- Anna, no.
I have my powers
to protect me. You don't.
Excuse me, I climbed
the North Mountain...
survived a frozen heart,
and saved you
from my ex-boyfriend...
and I did it
all without powers,
so, you know, I'm coming.
Me, too. I'll drive.
I'll bring the snacks!
I will look
after your people.
Please make sure they stay
out of the kingdom
until we return.
Of course.
Let's let them know.
Anna, I am worried
for her.
We have always feared
Elsa's powers were too much
for this world.
Now, we must pray
they are enough.
I won't let anything
happen to her.
Hyah!
Who's into trivia?
I am. Okay.
Did you know that water
has memory? True fact.
It's disputed by many,
but it's true.
Did you know
men are six times
more likely to be
struck by lightning?
Did you know gorillas
burp when they're happy?
Did you know we blink
four million times a day?
Did you know
wombats poop squares?
sleeping quietly
on long journeys
prevents insanity?
- Yeah, that's not true.
- It is.
- It's true.
- Definitely true.
No, it's the truth.
Well,
that was unanimous.
But I will look it up
when we get home.
They're both asleep.
So, what do you
wanna do?
Sven, keep us steady,
will ya?
- Hmm...
- Anna. Ahem.
- Anna?
- Mm-hmm?
Remember
our first trip like this...
when I said
you'd have to be crazy
to want to marry
a man you just met?
Wait, what? Crazy?
You didn't say I was crazy.
You think I'm crazy?
No. I did.
- You were...
- Huh?
...not crazy.
Clearly.
Just naive.
Not naive. Just, uh,
new to love. Like I was.
And when you're new,
you're bound to get it wrong.
So you're saying
I'm wrong for you.
What? No, no.
I'm not saying
you're wrong, or crazy.
- Kristoff, stop. Please.
- Good idea.
I hear it.
I hear the voice.
You do?
Olaf, wake up.
- Whoa.
- Wow.
Whoa! What the...
Whoa.
Promise me,
we do this together, okay?
I promise.
It's okay.
Did you know
that an enchanted forest
is a place
of transformation?
I have no idea
what that means...
but I can't wait to see
what it's gonna do
to each one of us.
- Hey!
- What is this?
- No pushing.
- Stop it.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- It's too fast.
What was that?
No. No, no, no.
And we're locked in.
Probably should have seen
that one coming.
This forest is beautiful.
Ooh.
The dam. It still stands.
It was
in Grand Pabbie's visions.
But why?
I don't know, but it's still
in good shape. Thank goodness.
What do you mean?
Well, if that dam broke...
it would send
a tidal wave so big
it would wash away
everything on this fjord.
Everything?
But Arendelle's
on this fjord.
Nothing's gonna happen
to Arendelle, Anna.
It's gonna be fine.
Come here.
You know,
under different circumstances,
this would be a, uh,
pretty romantic place.
Don't you think?
Different circumstances?
You mean,
like with someone else?
What? No! No.
I'm saying...
Just in case we don't
make it out of here...
Wait, what?
You don't think we're gonna
make it out of here?
No. No!
I mean, no,
we will make it out of here.
Well, technically the odds
are kind of complicated,
but my point is...
In case we die...
- You think we're gonna die?
- No! No, no, no.
- Where's Elsa?
- We will die at some point.
I swore that
I wouldn't leave her side.
Not in any
recent time will we die.
- Elsa!
- But way far in the future,
we will die.
Don't patronize me.
Elsa!
There you are.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
Okay, good.
Where's Olaf?
Um...
Anna?
Elsa?
Sven?
Samantha?
I don't even know
a Samantha.
Whoa!
Mm.
That's normal.
What was that?
Samantha?
♪ This will all make sense
when I am older
♪ Someday I will see
that this makes sense
♪ One day when I'm old and wise
I'll think back and realize
♪ That these were all
completely normal events!
♪ I'll have all the answers
when I'm older
♪ Like why we're in this
dark enchanted wood
♪ I know in a couple years
♪ These will seem
like childish fears
♪ And so I know
this isn't bad, it's good
♪ Excuse me
♪ Growing up means adapting
♪ Puzzling out your world
and your place
♪ When I'm more mature
I'll feel totally secure
♪ Being watched by something
with a creepy, creepy face
♪ See, that will all make
sense when I am older
♪ So there's no need
to be terrified or tense
♪ I'll just dream about a time
♪ When I'm in my aged prime
♪ 'Cause when you're older
♪ Absolutely everything
makes sense! ♪
This is fine.
- Whoa!
- Olaf!
Hey, guys.
Meet the Wind Spirit.
Coming through!
Ooh, I think
I'm gonna be sick.
I'd hold your hair back,
but I can't find my arms.
Hey! Stop!
Elsa!
Let her go!
Anna,
be careful!
That's my sister!
Prince Agnarr!
For Arendelle.
Look out!
Father!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
What are these?
Oh, they look like
moments in time.
What's that thing
you say, Olaf?
The thing... Oh!
My theory about
advancing technologies
as both our savior
and our doom?
No, not that one.
The one about...
- The one about cucumbers?
- No.
The thing about water.
Oh! Yeah.
Water has memory.
The water that
makes up you and me
has passed through
at least four humans...
and/or animals before us.
Hmm.
And remembers everything.
The wind's back.
Delicious.
I think
I'll name you Gale.
Get out of there. Whoa!
- Oh. Hi.
- Aren't you curious?
You in a better mood now?
Father.
That's Father.
This girl.
She's saving him.
She's Northuldra.
What is that?
Olaf, get behind me.
What are you gonna
do with that?
I have no idea.
Lower your weapon.
And you lower yours.
Arendellian soldiers?
Threatening my people,
Lieutenant?
Invading my dance space,
Yelena?
Why does that soldier
look so familiar?
No, no, no.
Lieutenant!
Get the sword!
That was magic.
Did you see that?
Of course I saw it.
You chose a nice,
cold greeting.
They've been trapped in
here this whole time?
- Yeah.
- What do we do now?
I got this.
Hi, I'm Olaf.
Oh, sorry. Yeah, I just
find clothes restricting.
Bet you're wondering who
we are and why we're here.
It's really quite simple.
It began with two sisters.
One born with magical powers.
One born powerless.
Their love of snowmen,
infinite.
Anna, no! Too high!
Blast!
Mama! Papa! Help!
Slam!
Doors shutting everywhere.
Sisters torn apart.
Well, at least
they have their parents.
Their parents are dead.
Oh.
Oh, hi. I'm Anna.
I'll marry a man I just met.
Elsa's gonna blow!
Snow! Snow! Aah, run!
Magic pulses
through my snowflakes.
I live.
Ice palace for one.
Get out, Anna.
Pew! Pew!
- My heart.
- Oh, my goodness.
Only an act
of true love can save you.
Here's
a true love's kiss.
You're not worth it.
Guess what?
I'm the bad guy.
What?
And Anna
freezes to death forever.
Oh, Anna.
Then she unfreezes!
Oh, and then Elsa woke up
the magical spirits...
and we were forced
out of our kingdom.
Now our only hope is to find
the truth about the past...
but we don't have a clue
how to do that...
except Elsa's hearing voices,
so we got that going for us.
Any questions?
I think they got it.
Are you really
Queen of Arendelle?
I am.
Why would nature reward
a person of Arendelle
with magic?
Perhaps to make up for the
actions of your people.
My people are innocent.
We would have never
attacked first.
May the truth be found.
- Mm...
- Hi. I'm sorry.
- Uh, what's happening?
- Hmm.
That's it.
Lieutenant Mattias!
Library, second portrait
on the left.
You were our father's
official guard.
Agnarr.
What did happen
to your parents?
Our parents' ship went
down in the Southern Sea...
six years ago.
I see him.
I see him in your faces.
Really?
Soldiers.
We may be getting on in years,
but we're still strong.
And proud to serve Arendelle.
Wait. Please.
Someone has called me here.
If I can just find them...
I believe
they have the answers
that may help us
free this forest.
Trust me,
I just want to help.
We only trust nature.
When nature speaks...
...we listen.
This will all
make sense when I'm older.
Fire Spirit!
Get back, everyone!
Head for the river!
No! No! No! The reindeer!
That's a dead end!
Come on, Sven!
We'll get them.
Elsa! Get out of there!
No, no, no.
Elsa!
Come on, buddy,
we can do this. Hyah!
Anna!
Oh!
Get her out of here.
No! Elsa!
They're all looking at us,
aren't they?
Got any advice?
Nothing?
Hmm. Should I know
what that means?
You hear it, too.
Somebody's calling us.
Who is it?
What do we do?
Okay, keep going north.
Elsa!
- Oh, thank goodness!
- Anna.
- Are you okay?
- What were you doing?
You could've been killed.
You can't just follow me
into fire.
You don't want me
to follow you into fire,
then don't run into fire.
You're not
being careful, Elsa.
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
I've been better.
Hmm. I know
what you need.
Where did you
get that scarf?
That's a Northuldra scarf.
What?
This is from one of
our oldest families.
It was our mother's.
Elsa.
I see it.
It's Mother.
Mother saved
Father's life that day.
Our mother was Northuldra.
We are called Northuldra.
We are the people of the sun.
I promise you I will
free this forest...
and restore Arendelle.
That's a pretty
big promise, Elsa.
Free the Forest?
Wow.
I'm sorry.
It's just, uh, some of us
were born in here,
we've never even seen
a clear sky.
I get it.
- The name's Ryder.
- Kristoff.
I heard the voice again.
We need to go north.
But the Earth Giants now
roam the north at night.
You can leave
in the morning.
I'm Honeymaren.
Honeymaren,
we'll do all we can.
Hey, let me ask you.
How do you guys cope...
with the ever-increasing
complexity of thought
that comes with maturity?
Brilliant!
Oh!
It's so refreshing to talk
to the youth of today.
Our future's
in bright hands.
Oh, no, no.
Don't chew that.
You don't know
what I've stepped in.
I can't seem
to get her attention.
Or even say
the right thing.
Well, you're in luck.
I know nothing
about women.
But I do know
that we have
the most amazing way
of proposing.
If we start now,
- we'll be ready by dawn.
- Really?
Best part,
it involves
a lot of reindeer.
Whoa.
Hey,
back at home...
Halima still over
at Hudson's Hearth?
She is.
Really?
She married?
Mm-mm.
Oh, wow. Why didn't that
make me feel better?
What else do you miss?
My father.
He passed
long before all this.
He was a great man.
Built us a good life
in Arendelle.
But taught me to never take
the good for granted.
He'd say, "Be prepared.
"Just when you think
you've found your way,
"life will throw you
onto a new path."
What do you do
when it does?
Don't give up.
Take it one step
at a time and...
Just do
the next right thing?
Yeah.
You got it.
I wanna show you
something. May I?
You know air, fire,
water, and earth.
Yes.
But, look,
there's a fifth spirit...
said to be a bridge between
us and the magic of nature.
A fifth spirit?
Some say
they heard it call out
the day the Forest fell.
My father heard it.
Do you think
that is who's calling me?
Maybe. Alas,
only Ahtohallan knows.
Ahtohallan.
♪ Dive down deep
into her sound
♪ But not too far
or you'll be drowned ♪
Why do lullabies
always have to have
some terrible
warning in them?
I wonder
that all the time.
Earth Giants.
What are they
doing down here?
Shh!
Hide.
They're coming!
This is why
we don't play with fire.
Oh, I can't stay mad at you.
Why are you so cute?
Please tell me you were not
about to follow them.
What if I can settle them
like I did the wind and fire?
Or what if
they can crush you
before you even
get the chance?
Remember, the goal
is to find the voice...
find the truth,
and get us home.
Hey, guys.
That was close.
I know.
The giants sensed me.
They may come back here.
I don't want to put anyone
at risk again.
And you're right, Anna.
We've got
to find the voice.
We're going now.
Okay. We're going.
Let me just...
Wait. Where are
Kristoff and Sven?
Oh, yeah. I think they
took off with that Ryder guy
and a bunch of reindeer.
- They left?
- Mm-hmm.
Just left
without saying anything?
Who knows
the ways of men?
Am I supposed to feel
this ridiculous?
Oh, yeah. Definitely.
Everyone ready?
Ready!
Uh,
I could use a rehearsal.
I love love.
Wait. You talk
for them, too?
I do.
It's like you can actually
hear what they're thinking.
Yeah. And then
you just say it.
And then you just say it.
Okay. Here she comes.
Princess Anna
of Arendelle...
my feisty, fearless,
ginger-sweet love.
Will you marry me?
Um...
No.
The princess left
with the queen.
What? Wait,
what? What?
I wouldn't try to follow.
They're long gone.
Long gone?
So, yeah.
Um, we're heading west
to the Lichen Meadows.
You can come with us
if you want.
Hey. Um...
I'm really sorry that...
- No, it's fine.
- Yeah. Yep.
Okay, I better go pack.
You coming with?
I'll just... Yeah,
I'll meet you there.
Okay, uh, you know
where you're going, right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yep.
I know the woods.
♪ Reindeers
are better than people
♪ Sven, why is love so hard?
♪ You feel what you feel
♪ And those feelings are real
♪ Come on, Kristoff
♪ Let down your guard
♪ Again, you're gone
♪ Off on a diff'rent path
than mine
♪ I'm left behind
♪ Wondering
if I should follow
♪ You had to go
♪ And, of course,
it's always fine
♪ I prob'ly could catch up
with you tomorrow
♪ But is this what it feels
like to be growing apart?
♪ When did I become the one
♪ Who's always
chasing your heart?
♪ Now I turn around and find
♪ I am lost in the woods
♪ North is South
Right is left
♪ When you're gone
♪ I'm the one
who sees you home
♪ But now I'm lost
in the woods
♪ And I don't know
what path you are on
♪ I'm lost in the woods
♪ Up till now
♪ The next step
was a question of how
♪ I never thought it was
a question of whether
♪ Who am I
♪ If I'm not your guy?
♪ Where am I
if we're not together?
♪ Forever
♪ Now I know
you're my true North
♪ 'Cause I am
lost in the woods
♪ Up is down
Day is night
♪ When you're not there
♪ Oh, you're my only landmark
♪ So I'm lost in the woods
♪ Wondering if you still care
♪ But I'll wait
♪ For a sign
- ♪ For a sign
- ♪ That I'm your path
- ♪ 'Cause you are mine
- ♪ You are mine
♪ Until then
- ♪ I'm lost in the woods
- ♪ Lost in the woods
♪ In the woods
Lost in the woods
♪ I'm lost in the woods
♪ Lost in the woods
I'm lost
♪ I'm lost in the woods ♪
Hey, Olaf, um,
maybe just one of you should do it.
I agree.
She's a little pitchy.
Hey, Gale's back.
What?
How can it be?
What is it?
Mother
and Father's ship.
But this isn't
the Southern Sea.
No, it isn't.
Why is their ship here?
How is it here?
It must have been washed in
from the Dark Sea.
What were they doing
in the Dark Sea?
I don't know.
How did the ship
get through the mist?
I thought nobody could but us.
Unless nobody was on it.
There's gotta be
something here.
Wait. Wait.
Look around.
Every Arendellian ship
has a compartment.
Waterproof.
That's very clever.
Although,
it does make me wonder
why they don't just make
the whole ship waterproof.
Here.
What language is this?
I don't know.
But look,
this is Mother's handwriting.
"The end of the ice age.
"The river found, but lost.
"Magic's source.
Elsa's source?"
It's a map.
They traveled north
and planned to cross
the Dark Sea to...
Ahtohallan.
It's real?
Octa-who-what?
Ahtohallan.
It's a magical river
said to hold all the
answers about the past.
Reinforcing my "water
has memory" theory. Mm.
Water has memory.
Elsa?
I wanna know
what happened to them.
Ahtohallan has to be
the source of her magic.
We keep going
for Elsa.
The waves are too high!
- Iduna!
- Agnarr!
Elsa!
Hey, hey, hey,
what are you doing?
This is my fault.
They were looking
for answers about me.
You are not responsible
for their choices, Elsa.
No. Just their deaths.
Stop. No.
Yelena asked,
why would the spirits
reward Arendelle
with a magical queen?
Because our mother
saved our father.
She saved her enemy.
Her good deed
was rewarded with you.
You are a gift.
For what?
If anyone can resolve
the past...
if anyone can save Arendelle
and free this forest,
it's you.
I believe in you, Elsa.
More than anyone or anything.
Honeymaren said
there was a fifth spirit.
A bridge between
the magic of nature and us.
A fifth spirit?
That's who's been calling
me from Ahtohallan.
The answers about the
past are all there.
So we go to Ahtohallan.
Not "we."
- Me.
- What?
The Dark Sea is too
dangerous for us both.
No. No!
We do this together.
Remember the song?
"Go too far and
you'll be drowned."
Who will stop you
from going too far?
You said you believed in me,
that this is
what I was born to do.
And I don't wanna
stop you from that.
I... I don't
wanna stop you
from being whatever
you need to be.
I just don't want
you dying...
trying to be everything
for everyone else, too.
Don't do this alone.
Let me help you, please.
I can't lose you, Elsa.
I can't lose you
either, Anna.
- Come on.
- Mmm.
Wait, what?
What are you doing?
Elsa!
No! No!
Olaf, help me stop.
Give me a hand.
- Hang on!
- Whoa!
Wait. Wait!
No! No! No!
Oh, come on!
Anna,
this might sound crazy...
but I'm sensing
some rising anger.
Well, I am angry, Olaf!
She promised me
we'd do this together!
Yeah. Uh-huh.
But what I mean is,
I'm sensing rising anger in me.
Wait, you're angry?
Um, I... I think so.
Elsa pushed me away,
too,
and didn't even
say goodbye.
And you have every right
to be very, very mad at her.
And you said some things
never change.
But since then,
everything's done nothing
but change.
I know.
But look, I'm still here
holding your hand.
Yeah,
that's a good point, Anna.
I feel better.
You're such a good listener.
Don't shush me. That's rude.
No! No!
Oh. The Giants.
They're huge.
- Hang on, Olaf.
- Huh?
Try not
to scream.
Found it.
Thank you.
Where are we?
In a pit
with no way out.
But with a spooky,
pitch-black way in.
Come on,
it'll be fun.
Assuming we don't
get stuck here forever,
no one ever finds us...
and you starve
and I give up.
But, bright side,
Elsa's gotta be doing
a whole lot
better than we are.
Okay.
Oh.
Whoa!
No!
Of course.
Glaciers are
rivers of ice.
Ahtohallan is frozen.
I hear you.
And I'm coming.
♪ Every inch of me
is trembling
♪ But not from the cold
♪ Something is familiar
♪ Like a dream I can
reach but not quite hold
♪ I can sense you there
♪ Like a friend
I've always known
♪ I'm arriving
♪ And it feels like
I am home
♪ I have always
been a fortress
♪ Cold secrets deep inside
♪ You have secrets, too
♪ But you don't have to hide
♪ Show yourself
♪ I'm dying to meet you
♪ It's your turn
♪ Are you the one I've been
looking for all of my life?
♪ Show yourself
♪ I'm ready to learn
♪ I've never felt so certain
♪ All my life I've been torn
♪ But I'm here for a reason
♪ Could it be the reason
I was born?
♪ I have always been
so different
♪ Normal rules did not apply
♪ Is this the day?
Are you the way
♪ I finally find out why?
♪ Show yourself!
♪ I'm no longer trembling
♪ Here I am
♪ I've come so far
♪ You are the answer
I've waited for
♪ All of my life
♪ Oh, show yourself!
♪ Let me see who you are
♪ Come to me now
♪ Open your door
♪ Don't make me wait
♪ One moment more
♪ Oh, come to me now
♪ Open your door
♪ Don't make me wait
♪ One moment more
♪ Where the Northwind
♪ Meets the sea
♪ There's a river
♪ Full of memory
Mother.
♪ Come, my darling,
homeward bound
♪ I am found!
♪ Show yourself
♪ Step into your power
♪ Grow yourself
♪ Into something new
♪ You are the one
you've been waiting for
- ♪ All of my life
- ♪ All of your life
♪ Oh, show yourself! ♪
Hi, I'm Olaf.
And I like warm hugs.
I love you, Olaf!
Come on,
you can do it.
- ♪ Here I stand
- Oh.
♪ In the light of day ♪
Oh! Like a chicken
with the face of a monkey!
I just wasn't looking
where I was going.
But I'm great actually.
Prince Hans
of the Southern Isles.
I love you.
I need to tell you
about my past.
And where I'm from.
I'm listening.
Iduna!
What are you reading,
Your Majesty?
Oh, some new
Danish author.
King Runeard,
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
Grandfather?
We bring Arendelle's
full guard.
But they have given us no
reason not to trust them.
The Northuldra
follow magic.
Which means we can
never trust them.
Grandfather?
Magic makes people feel too powerful.
Too entitled.
It makes them think they
can defy the will of a king.
That is not
what magic does.
That's just your fear.
Fear is what
can't be trusted.
You see, the dam
will weaken their lands,
so they will
have to turn to me.
♪ Dive down
deep into her sound
♪ But not too far,
or you'll be drowned
They will come
in celebration.
And then, we will know
their size and strength.
As you have welcomed us,
we welcome you...
our neighbors, our friends.
King Runeard, the dam isn't
strengthening our waters.
It's hurting the Forest.
It's cutting off
the North...
Let... Let's not
discuss this here.
Let's meet on the fjord.
Have tea.
Find a solution.
No!
Anna!
Hmm. Which lucky tunnel
do we choose?
You see, the dam
will weaken their lands,
so they will
have to turn to me.
King Runeard, the dam,
it's hurting the Forest.
Elsa's found it.
What is it?
The truth about the past.
That's my grandfather...
attacking
the Northuldra leader...
who wields no weapon.
The dam wasn't
a gift of peace.
It was a trick.
But that goes
against everything
Arendelle stands for.
It does, doesn't it?
I know how to free
the Forest.
I know what we have to do
to set things right.
Why do you say that
so sadly?
We have to break the dam.
But Arendelle
will be flooded.
That's why everyone
was forced out.
To protect them
from what has to be done.
Oh. Oh!
Are you okay?
I could really use
a bright side, Olaf.
Bright side? Um...
Turtles can breathe
through their butts.
- Huh?
- And I see a way out.
I knew I could
count on you.
Come on, Olaf, Elsa's probably
on her way back right now.
We can meet her and...
Olaf?
What's this?
Are you okay?
I'm flurrying?
Wait. No. That's...
That's not it.
I'm flurrying away.
The magic in me is fading.
What?
I don't think Elsa's okay.
I think...
she may have gone too far.
No. No.
Anna?
I'm sorry.
You're gonna have to do
this next part on your own.
- Okay?
- Wait.
Come here.
- I've got you.
- Oh.
That's good.
Hey, Anna?
I just thought of one thing
that's permanent.
What's that?
Love.
Warm hugs?
I like warm hugs.
I love you.
Olaf? Elsa?
What do I do now?
♪ I've seen dark before
♪ But not like this
♪ This is cold This
is empty This is numb
♪ The life I knew
is over
♪ The lights are out
♪ Hello, darkness
♪ I'm ready to succumb
♪ I follow you around
♪ I always have
♪ But you've gone to a place
I cannot find
♪ This grief has a gravity
♪ It pulls me down
♪ But a tiny voice
♪ Whispers in my mind
♪ You are lost
♪ Hope is gone
♪ But you must go on
♪ And do the next right thing
♪ Can there be a day
beyond this night?
♪ I don't know anymore
what is true
♪ I can't find my direction
I'm all alone
♪ The only star
that guided me was you
♪ How to rise
from the floor
♪ When it's not you
I'm rising for?
♪ Just do
the next right thing
♪ Take a step
♪ Step again
♪ It is all that I can
♪ To do the next right thing
♪ I won't look too far ahead
♪ It's too much
for me to take
♪ But break it down
to this next breath
♪ This next step
♪ This next choice
is one that I can make!
♪ So I'll walk through
this night
♪ Stumbling blindly
toward the light
♪ And do
the next right thing
♪ And with the dawn
♪ What comes then?
♪ When it's clear
that everything
♪ Will never be
the same again?
♪ Then I'll make the choice
♪ To hear that voice
♪ And do
♪ The next right thing ♪
Wake up!
That's it.
Come and get me!
Come on!
Over here!
That's right.
Keep coming.
Keep coming!
That'll work.
This way, guys!
What?
No, no, no, no.
She's leading them to the dam.
Kristoff!
I'm here.
What do you need?
- To get to the dam.
- You got it.
Thank you.
Come on. Come on.
01:19: life I knew
is over
♪ The lights are out
♪ Hello, darkness
♪ I'm ready to succumb
♪ I follow you around
♪ I always have
♪ But you've gone to a place
I cannot find